Matti Salokangas

matti.salokangas@gmail.com | 541.291.8826 | www.sturdynut.com

Summary

- Full stack software developer that excels in UI/UX, communication and leadership with 12+ years of professional experience.
- Successfully lead a team of 3 software developers in building out an internal business portal and several online stores.
- Worked on an international team to build the next generation of a large enterprise digital marketing platform that was praised for it's "Intuitive user interface" by gartner.com.
- Designed and built an online drink menu for the largest privately held drive-through coffee chain in the United States.

Technical Skills

Software Development	UI / UX	Project Management/ Leadership
Languages: Javascript CSS/SCSS/Stylus HTML/Pug/Slim C#/VB.NET Ruby	Tools: Sketch, XD, Studio, Photoshop, Illustrator, Balsamiq Mockups, Google Analytics, Mixpanel, Inspectlet	Tools: Jira, Pivotal Tracker, Trello, Wrike, whiteboards
SPA Frameworks: React, Angular, Ember	Wireframes, user stories, conducting user interviews	Scrum / Agile: Pair programming Test Driven Development
APIS/Cloud: REST, GraphQL, Firebase, AWS	Building and iterating on prototypes	Excellent at delegation, budget and keeping on track
Backend: Node, .NET, Ruby on Rails	Low-high fidelity UI Design	Empathetic, communicative and positive servant leader
Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL	Tracking and monitoring user engagement	Enjoy mentoring and helping others grow

Professional Experience

Senior Developer

CompanionLabs | August 2018 - Present | Remote

- Lead UI/UX in conjunction with Google to build out CompanionLabs Google product.
- Reduced application bundle size by 300%+ through bundle analysis and optimizations to code base.
- Maintain and help define new features through user stories, interviews and rapidly iterating on prototypes.

Technology: React, Node, GraphQL, AWS, PostgreSQL

Senior Web Developer / Web Development Manager

Dutch Bros Coffee | May 2017 - August 2018 | Grants Pass, OR

- Lead a team of 3 developers in building an internal business portal and multiple custom storefronts.
- Built a financial reporting application that provided P&L statements and comparisons among 300+ stores.
- Mentored other developers through 1-on-1's, technical training and leading by example.
- Managed projects using Trello and Wrike.

Technology: Javascript, Node, React, PHP, Shopify, MS SQL Server

UI/UX Engineer

IgnitionOne | July 2015 - March 2017 | Remote

- Successfully worked on a large, international team to rebuild IgnitionOne's flagship Display platform working with domestic and international teams.
- Worked directly with Creative Director in defining UI components and style guide.
- Created an in-house solution for capturing screenshots of advertisements for previews used within the Display platform.

Technology: Angular, Node, Stylus, Jade, Gulp, Webpack, Bootstrap, Npm and Bower.

UI/UX Engineer

Coding Zeal | August 2014 - July 2015 | Remote / Medford, OR

- Built an app for OneSight.org utilizing head tracking technology to simulate nearsightedness as part of a campaign to raise awareness of blindness.
- Created a file uploader application for a dental company using Ruby on Rails.
- Implemented a solution for managing schedules for a mobile vet clinic using Ember.

Technology: Ruby on Rails, Ember, Javascript

Owner

Symplex | January 2014 - Present | Grants Pass, OR

Responsible for all aspects of work from requirements gathering, design, development to hosting and maintaining a healthy relationship with clients.

- Built an order management system using Ruby on Rails for a local coffee shop.
- Built a social network for motorcycle riders.

Technology: Ruby on Rails, Javascript

Consulting Software Engineer

Knotice | July 2013 - January 2014 Grants Pass, OR

- Built landing pages for **Charter Communications**, include a promotion for Anchorman 2
- Built a marketing campaign scheduling app for **Dollar General**.

Technology: Node, ASP.NET, MVC and SQL Server.

UI/UX Designer

Motorcycle Superstore | February 2013 - July 2013 | Medford, OR

- Designed and help rebuild motorcyclesuperstore.com to be a responsive ecommerce site.
- Develop and iterate on concepts for web, mobile, and tablet design experiences in a fast-paced team environment.
- Develop and contribute to wireframes, mockups, and interactive prototypes.
- Production of designs and documents for presentation to developers, managers, and senior executives.
- Refined designs, considering live customer data, market research, and usability studies.

Software Engineer II / Senior Software Engineer

Knotice Ltd | January 2008 - July 2012 | Akron, OH

- Created a system for generating mobile-friendly microsites that were triggered via a Microsoft Tag on **Canon** printer boxes.
 - The mobile web sites were featured on time square in NYC.
- Developed a REST and SOAP API for the marketing platforms core services, including email sends, content creation, user management, sns and reporting.
- Developed a suite of custom Web Controls used by other developers for rapid development of custom one-off web applications. Custom controls included a gridview, autocomplete, tooltip, modal dialog, paging, listview, textbox and buttons.

Test Automation Engineer / Software Engineer II

2004 - 2008 OEConnection LLC July 2004 - August 2008

- Defined and built a test automation framework for testing a suite of web based products.
- Built software for selling parts between dealerships.
- Worked with multiple teams to define code quality standards to ensure testability.

Education

Bloc | 2015 - 2016 iOS App Development

DeVry University | 2005 - 2007 | Summa Cum Laude

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems, Web Application Development

Boulder Outdoor Survival School | 2014

Wilderness First Responder, Wilderness Medicine

- 40 Hours of Wilderness Medicine Training
- Certified Wilderness First Responder

Buckeye High School/Medina County Career Center | 2000 - 2004

- Courses covered Visual Studio 6.0, HTML, CSS, Windows 2000 Professional and
- Server, FrontPage, Networking and Microsoft Network Components and Internal
- PC Hardware and Advanced Level College Preparation.

Technical Training Courses

- Scrum Inc. 40 Hour Training Course
- 2124 Programming with C#.Net
- IC3 Computer and Internet Fundamentals Certified
- Certificate of Competency as a Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator
- WinRunner 7.6 Suite Training Course

Awards

OEConnection, LLC - The Gold Star Award - Acts of Brilliance

"Demonstrated flexibility and diligence in conducting integration and user acceptance testing with General Motors."

OEConnection, LLC - The Gold Star Award - Acts of Brilliance

"Went above and beyond to aid the Quality Assurance team with testing."

Memberships

- Grants Pass Drink and Code
- Cleveland .NET Special Interest Group
- Cleveland SQL Special Interest Group
- Business Professionals of America
- Boy Scouts of America